Joey Gryder

Sr. Software Engineer in Test

Technical Lead - QA Team

Joey Gryder

Mt. Pleasant, SC

joey.gryder@gmail.com https://www.joeygryder.com

Skills

I have experience in many programming languages and paradigms. My primary focus has been on object-oriented languages when building testing frameworks and in-house tools, with several years experience each in VB / C# .NET and Ruby.

I am well versed in various AWS cloud service offerings, with a recent interest in Lambda and Serverless technologies. In the past year, I have also built applications utilizing React, MySQL, and DynamoDB.

Experience

BoomTown ROI / Sr. Software Engineer in Test - Technical LeadAUGUST 2014 - PRESENT, CHARLESTON, SC

Responsible for the architecture and implementation of the first test automation framework at BoomTown, built with Cucumber, React, Sinatra, Docker, and AWS.

Helped grow the QA engineering team from two initial SETs to a staff of over ten engineers, through internal training and promotions of QA Analysts, as well as external hiring of new engineering graduates.

Served as the subject matter expert for the team on web application test automation through Selenium WebDriver.

Blackbaud / Sr. Software Quality Engineer

JUNE 2011 - AUGUST 2014, CHARLESTON, SC

Contributed to an internally maintained WPF / VB.NET application used by manual testers to interface with SOAP-based web services.

Built a Bootstrap / jQuery / MVC.NET testing dashboard to allow for the execution and storage of test automation results.

Load-tested various back-end services responsible for Blackbaud's payment processing and e-mail systems.

Implemented an in-house mobile application testing lab using Selenium Grid, Appium, and various iOS and Android devices.

Education

Appalachian State University / B.S. in Computer Science

JANUARY 2009 - MAY 2011, BOONE, NC Summa Cum Laude

UNC Asheville / B.A. in Political Science

AUGUST 2003 - MAY 2007. ASHEVILLE, NC